Nicholas Russo

1-925-699-1715 | <u>nijaru0x@gmail.com</u> | <u>https://nijaru.com</u>

SUMMARY

I'm a self-taught software developer with two and a half years of professional experience. I have a breadth of knowledge covering python, go, linux, and building APIs. I'm a strong learner who focuses on writing clean and correct code. I am interested in Linux, APIs, AI, networking, databases, and distributed systems.

SKILLS

- Programming languages: Python, Go, C, C++, Ruby, JavaScript
- · Web frameworks: Flask, Django, Ruby on Rails
- Cloud platforms: AWS, GCP, DigitalOcean, Heroku
- Operating Systems: Redhat, Fedora, Ubuntu, Gentoo
- Databases: SQLite, PostgreSQL, Redis
- Containerization: Docker, CoreOS
- Command Line Tools: Git, Bash, zsh, neovim

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Omnitier, Inc.

January 2021 - May 2023

- Designed and developed a public Python API for a Go and gRPC backend for automation and scripting of our software.
- Built a regression testing system on top of the Python API ensuring stability and reliability.
- Improved our React frontend by implementing small features and bug fixes.
- Optimized a Python script's runtime from 45+ minutes to 5 minutes by reducing system calls while traversing the filesystem.

IT Support Intern

Robert Half

June 2011 - December 2011

• Performed installations of workstations and software. Repaired laptops and desktops.

IT Intern

City of Pleasanton

January 2010 - May 2010

• Performed routine IT tasks. Assisted in a thin client deployment to the city's library.

AWARDS

Money 20/20 Las Vegas Kairos - 2nd Place Winner

October 2016

• Built a cross-terminal payment application and API for partnering businesses together using Go and PostgreSQL and deployed it on CoreOS using Docker.

EDUCATION

Las Positas College, Livermore, CA — Computer Science	2014 - 2015, 2016 - 2018
Computer Science Club President	2016 - 2017
42 Silicon Valley, Fremont, CA — Computer Science	2018 - 2020
Dev Bootcamp, San Francisco, CA — Web Development	Fall 2016 - Spring 2017
Chabot College, Hayward, CA — Music Recording Technology	2013-2014